californiasunday.com 2018-10-20

# Privacy Policy –

This is the Privacy Policy for California Sunday, updated October 1, 2014. Our previous privacy policy can be found here

California Sunday is committed to preserving the privacy of its readers and users. This policy outlines the collection, use, and storage of users’ personal information that is submitted at any point on any California Sunday website or mobile application (collectively, the “Site”).

### Consent

By accessing the Site, you consent to the use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. Except as set forth in this policy, your personal Information will not be used for any other purpose without your consent. We will not sell customer lists or otherwise provide your personal information to third parties for third party marketing purposes. You may delete your California Sunday account at any time. However, deleting your account may result in your inability to continue using the Site and/or other services. If you would like to delete your account, please email [support@californiasunday.com](mailto:support@californiasunday.com). If you no longer wish to receive marketing emails from us, you can click on the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of all of our marketing emails.

### Types and uses of personal information

In order to purchase a story on the Site, you must first create an account with a username and password. The registration system requires a valid email address–used to confirm the account and to contact you with information about your account and as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy. If you subscribe to receive the print magazine, we will collect your name and mailing address in order to send you the magazine. Accounts may be backed up regularly, if the user changes the information on his or her account, California Sunday’s stored data backups may include the user’s original information for up to six months. Separately, when any California Sunday administrators are emailed, the addresses and correspondence are retained. This information may be saved to respond to issues and inquiries of all types.

### Credit card information

For collecting and processing payments for purchase of California Sunday stories and subscriptions, we utilize Service Providers (defined below). Our Service Providers will collect personal information needed to process those payments. California Sunday does not store any user credit card information on our own servers.

### Aggregate Data Collection

The California Sunday application on iOS, Android, and other devices, as well as the California Sunday web reader, may collect certain non-personally identifiable information, such as how you utilize the app and how long and which multimedia components you take advantage of. California Sunday anonymizes this information and does not connect it to your identity. This data is used to enable us to understand broad trends in how people are reading and utilizing our content, in order to better serve our readers. If you prefer that the California Sunday app not collect any anonymized information about your reading habits in our iOS apps, you can go to Settings → Apps → California Sunday → Disable Analytics Data Collection, and turn it off. We collect information regarding the actions you take on the Site. For example, each time you use the Site we automatically collect the type of Web browser you use, your operating system, your Internet Service Provider, your IP address, the pages you view, and the time and duration of your visits to the Site. We use this information to help us understand how people use the Site, and to enhance the services we offer. We use Google Analytics to collect and analyze some of this information and other non-identifying information. For more information about Google Analytics, please visit [www.google.com/ policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/%20policies/privacy/partners/).

### Mailing list

If you send us your email address to be added to our list, we will not share it with anyone outside of California Sunday Inc., except as provided in this Privacy Policy. We use email addresses only to send occasional updates on our latest stories and other news about the California Sunday and its stories that we think our readers might be interested in.

### Information sharing

Aggregated reading and demographic information about our audience may be shared with third parties, including browser information and traffic statistics. This data is not tied to any individual readers’ accounts or personally identifiable information. From time to time, we may establish a business relationship with other businesses whom we believe trustworthy and who have confirmed that their privacy practices are consistent with ours (“Service Providers”). For example, we may contract with Service Providers to provide certain services, such as hosting and maintenance, data storage and management, and marketing and promotions. We only provide our Service Providers with the information necessary for them to perform these services on our behalf. Each Service Provider must agree to use reasonable security procedures and practices, appropriate to the nature of the information involved, in order to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Service Providers are prohibited from using personal information other than as specified by California Sunday. California Sunday cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We may disclose personal information and any other information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties if, in our discretion, we believe it is necessary or appropriate in order to respond to legal requests (including court orders and subpoenas), to protect the safety, property, or rights of California Sunday or of any third party, to prevent or stop any illegal, unethical, or legally actionable activity, or to comply with the law. We may share personal and other information with businesses controlling, controlled by, or under common control with California Sunday. If California Sunday is merged, acquired, or sold, or in the event of a transfer of some or all of our assets, we may disclose or transfer personal and other information in connection with such transaction. You will have the opportunity to opt out of any such transfer if, in our discretion, the new entity plans to handle your information in a way that differs materially from this Privacy Policy.

### Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. California Sunday uses cookies on the Site. Some of the information stored in cookies is sometimes linked to readers’ accounts. California Sunday uses both session cookies and persistent cookies. A session cookie expires within a limited period of time. Session cookies are used so that readers with accounts can navigate the Site without logging in multiple times over a short period of time. A persistent cookie remains on the user’s hard drive or device for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies are used to recognize account holders and present the Site accordingly. Users can remove cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file.

### Advertising and Online Tracking

We may allow third-party companies to serve ads and collect certain anonymous information when you visit the Site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, web browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to the Site and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third-party web beacon to collect this information. Our systems do not recognize browser “Do Not Track” signals, but several of our Service Providers who utilize these cookies or web beacons on our Site enable you to opt out of targeted advertising practices. To learn more about these advertising practices or to opt out of this type of advertising, you can visit [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) or [www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). We also provide you with additional tools to opt out of marketing from us. You can learn about this in the “Consent” section of this Privacy Policy.

### Security

We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect the confidentiality and security of information transmitted to us. However, no data transmission over the Internet or other network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect information transmitted on or through the Site, we cannot and do not guarantee the security of any information you transmit on or through the Site, and you do so at your own risk.

### Links To Other Websites

The Site may contain links to other websites or allow others to send you such links. A link to a third party’s website does not mean that we endorse it or that we are affiliated with it. We do not exercise control over third-party websites. You access such third-party websites or content at your own risk. You should always read the privacy policy of a third-party website before providing any information to the website.

### Children’s Privacy

The Site is intended for users who are 18 years old or older. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete such information from our records.

### Processing in the United States

Please be aware that your personal information and communications may be transferred to and maintained on servers or databases located outside your state, province, or country. If you are located outside of the United States, please be advised that we process and store all information in the United States. The laws in the United States may not be as protective of your privacy as those in your location. By using the Site, you agree that the collection, use, transfer, and disclosure of your personal information and communications will be governed by the applicable laws in the United States.

### Privacy Policy Changes

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will inform you by posting the revised Privacy Policy on the Site. Those changes will go into effect on the date shown in the revised Privacy Policy. By continuing to use the Site, you consent to the revised Privacy Policy.

### Other questions or issues

If you have any questions or issues around any of these matters, email us: [support@californiasunday.com](mailto:support@californiasunday.com).

### Legal

All stories and other information are © 2014-2015 California Sunday, Inc. All rights reserved.
